Okay now lets talk about
Bây giờ nói về
Elastic Network Interfaces or ENI.
Elastic Network Interface hay ENI.
So if you hear me say ENI I mean
Tôi nói ENI tức là
Elastic Network Interfaces.
Elastic Network Interface.
They're a logical component in a VPC
Đây là thành phần logic trong VPC
and they represent a virtual network card.
đại diện cho card mạng ảo.
So they're what gives EC2 Instances access to the network,
Nó giúp EC2 instance kết nối mạng,
but they're used outside EC2 Instances as well
và cũng được dùng ngoài EC2
as we'll see later in this course.
như ta sẽ thấy sau này.
So for example we have an availability zone
Ví dụ chúng ta có một Availability Zone
and we have one EC2 Instance
và một EC2 instance
and to it is attached on eth0, your primary ENI
gắn ENI chính ở eth0
and this will provide your EC2 Instance network connectivity
cung cấp kết nối mạng và private IP.
and for example, a private IP.
Mỗi ENI có các thuộc tính sau.
So each ENI can have the following attributes.
Nó có một IPv4 private chính
Number one it can have a Primary private IPv4
và có thể có IPv4 private phụ.
and one or more secondary IPv4. Okay.
Trong ví dụ này tôi chỉ có một,
So in this example, I have one of zero but
nhưng bạn có thể thêm ENI thứ hai
you are more than welcomed to add a secondary ENI to EC2
tạo eth1 và có thêm private IPv4.
and that will be eth1
Mỗi ENI cũng có thể có Elastic IPv4
and this will give you another private IPv4 as well, okay. `
cho từng private IPv4
Each ENI can also have an elastic IPv4 per private IPv4
hoặc một hay nhiều public IPv4.
or one or more public IPv4,
Nó cung cấp cả private và public IP
so it gives you a private and a public IP
như ta sẽ thấy trong phần thực hành.
as will see in the hands-on.
Bạn có thể gắn một hay nhiều security group
You can have one or more security groups attached
cho ENI.
to your ENI.
Nó có địa chỉ MAC
You can have a Mac address attached to it
và những thứ khác,
and other things but I've just give you
nhưng đây là phần quan trọng nhất.
the most important bits right now in this lecture.
Bạn có thể tạo ENI độc lập
And you can create ENI's independently from
và gắn vào EC2 khi cần
your EC2 instances
hoặc chuyển giữa các instance
and attach them on the fly
để failover.
or move them from EC2 instances for failover.
Chúng ta xem nó trông ra sao.
So, let's have a look at what it looks like.
ENI bị ràng buộc
And by the way, they're bounded
với một Availability Zone.
to a specific availability zone or AZ.
Nếu tạo ENI ở một AZ,
So that means that if you create a ENI in the specific AZ,
bạn chỉ gắn nó trong AZ đó.
you can only have it bound to that specific AZ.
Đây là EC2 khác
So here's another issue to instance
có ENI khác gắn kèm.
and it has another ENI attached to it.
Ta có thể chuyển eth1
And for example, we can do is we can move eth1
từ instance đầu sang instance thứ hai
from the first EC2 instance into the second EC2 Instance
để chuyển private IP đó.
to move that private IP.
Tức là private IP sẽ rời
And what it means is that that private IP will change
instance thứ nhất và gắn vào thứ hai.
from the first issue to instance
Rất hữu ích cho failover.
and will be attached to the second EC2 Instance.
Nếu instance được truy cập
And it's very very helpful for failovers.
bằng private static IP,
For example, if you're easy to instance is accessed
bạn có thể chuyển IP giữa hai máy
by a private static IP,
để failover.
then you can move the IP around between
Vậy hãy xem phần hands-on
these two instances for failover purposes, okay.
để thấy rõ điều này.
So let's have a look in the hands-on
Và bây giờ
to see what it looks like.
chúng ta bắt đầu xem nó hoạt động ra sao.